I like Uehara.
なお (菜緒) 私は上原君のことが好きなの うえはら
Oh!
あつ
-Uhm... -How's your fever?
(菜緒)あつあのさ… (上愿お前熱は?
Did he hear me?
聞こえてたのか. 聞こえてないのか.
Which is it?
どっちなの
-Argh! -What? Did you say something?
ああ~ ! (上原)何?何か言った?
He heard.
聞こえてる 聞こえてない
Yes!
よし
Oh. Yours is in the fridge.
あつお前の分 冷蔵庫に入ってっから
Oh, thank you.
うん ありがとう
By the way,
あのさ さっき公園で話してたこと
what I said in the park just now, did you?
き…聞こえてないよね? 仩原) うん
Thank goodness.
ハア...よかった
I did hear you say that you liked me, or something like that.
お前が俺のこと 好きとか言ってるのは聞こえたけど
What?
え
Oh no!
えつ
-You're faking it, right? -Huh?
フリだろ? (菜緒)へ?
Don't worry. I know you're not serious.
心配しなくても 本気にしねーって
Yeah, that's right.
そうだよね!
He would never give up unless you said that, right?
(上原)ああでも言わないと 諦めそうになかったもんなあいつ
Yes, yes. That's right.
そうそう そうなんだよ
I heard he's called the king of the love confession.
(上原)告白大王って 言われてるらしいじゃん
He falls in love with anyone and tells them he loves them.
ほれっぽくて 誰にでも告白するって
-I'm happy for you. -Huh?
(上原)でもよかったな つにな (菜緒)ん?
It's nice that there's someone that thinks you're attractive.
女として見てくれる奴がいて
What?
ハッ! ハツ
What're you so angry about? I was complimenting you.
何怒ってんだよお前 褒めてんじゃん
That's no compliment!
褒めてないでしょうが
Huh? I'm not laughing at you.
え?あついや
That Uehara can sure be stupid.
上原君って 結構とぼけた人なんだね
Well, I guess I'm glad about it.
まあよかったんだけどさ つにんに
But it kind of ticks me off that he doesn't think anything of me.
でも全然本気にされないのも どんなもんかね
Nao, you actually like Uehara, don't you?
菜緒さ本当は好きなんでしょ? 上原君のこと
I can tell. There's no need to hide it.
もう分かってるよ いいじゃん隠さなくたって
I'm not trying to hide it.
別に隠してなんかないし
I realized it myself recently.
私も最近気づいたから.
Finally, you accepted it.
や一つと認めた
Like I figured. I was in love with Uehara too.
そりゃね 私も上原君ラブだったし
So I know it was hard to tell me.
言い出しにくかったのも 分かるけど
-Sorry. -Now, you listen to me.
ごめん (まりな)言っとくけど
You're more important to me than Uehara is.
私は上原君より 菜緒のほうが大事だからね
Keeping it secret from me really made me sad.
秘密にされてるほうが よっぽど悲しいよ
Oh, Marina.
まりな
I'm so happy that I finally get to talk about love life with you.
いや~菜緒と恋バナできる日が 来るとはね
You look happy.
何かうれしい (菜緒)えへへ
What're you doing for New Year's?
(上原)お前年末年始どうすんの?
I'm planning to go to my parent's. You're going back too, right?
田舎帰る予定だけど 上原君も帰るよね?
No.
上原)いや 仩原)いや
My brother and Yuri are going to be in Hawaii on New Year's.
兄貴たち正月は ハワイでいないらしいから
-Hawaii? -They said it's their honeymoon.
(菜緒)ハワイ? (上原)新婚旅行だってさ
I see.
(菜緒)ふーん
-Then that means you're... -Working.
ってことは上原君. 仩原)バイト
Hourly wages go up during New Year's.
年末年始は時給アップだし
I'll probably get a New Year's bonus too.
お年玉も出るらしいから
-You're spending New Year's Eve here? -I'll just come home and go to bed.
ここで年越しするってこと? (上原)帰って寝るだけだけどな
Oh, I see.
そうなんだ
Make sure you do your New Year's cleaning before you go home.
(上原)お前田舎帰る前に ちゃんと大掃除していけよ
I will.
はーい
It's just so expensive to travel home during New Year's.
(菜緒)年末年始は 交通費高いじゃん
And I used way too much money to move in here.
それに引っ越しで お金いっぱい使いすぎちゃつたし
Plus I've got remedial lessons.
あと補習もあるし.
But, at least you can come home for New Year's Day and after.
(美紀子)でも… お正月くらいは帰れるでしょ
But, you see, they asked me to work then.
それがバイト入ってって 頼まれちゃつたんだよね つにんに
And spring vacation isn't that long after winter vacation.
ほら冬休み終わっても すぐ春休み来るじゃん
I guess so.
(美紀子)そうねえ... 今からじゃ
Plane tickets are really expensive during New Year's.
飛行機なんて高いよ 年末年始は
Oh, all right.
渼紀子)分かったわ
I'll send you some New Year's gift money.
お年玉送ってあげるから
Thank you, Mom. Bye.
ありがとうお母さん! じゃあね
This means... New Year's Eve with Uehara.
上原君と年越し
Happy New Year. I wish you all the best this year.
あけましておめでとう 今年もよろしくな
Me too.
うん
This is going to be so nice.
なーhKね
What? We're closed on New Year's?
えっ年末年始 バイトお休みなの?
On New Year's Eve, most people eat soba.
いっせい (一星)年越しっつったら 普通そばだろ
It's the only time ramen shops can take a nice break.
ラーメン屋は おとなしく休むに限る
Every year we're open till the 30th and start again on the third.
毎年30日が仕事納めで 年始は3日から
-No work, huh? -You're going home, aren't you?
(菜緒)バイトないんだ (一星)田舎帰るんだろ?
Huh?
(菜緒)え?
-Welcome!
(菜緒)いらっしゃい! (一星)いらっしゃい! しし
Oh!
休地おう! (菜緒)あつ おあ 大菜
-Daichi, what brings you here? -I'm hungry.
大ちゃん!どうしたの? (大地)腹減って
Actually, I'm a fan of this ramen now.
つーかここのラーメンの ファンになった
-Thanks for revisiting!
毎度!
-Here you go. -Looks great.
(菜緒)はいどうぞ (大地)いただきます
Thanks.
(菜緒)はーい
By the way, Nao--
菜緒さ (戸が開く音)
Welcome!
(菜緒)いらっしゃい…
-Abe. -What are you doing here, Nao?
あべっち? べつ (阿部)吉川!?何で? よしかわ
Well, I work here.
何でって 私ここでバイトしてるんだ
-Now I see. -Huh?
そういうことか (菜緒)ん?
I was talking to Mitsuishi.
いや光石が
He said since I was feeling down about being turned down by you
吉川にフラれて落ち込む俺に 教えてくれたのさ
that I should come here. He said I'd get over it for sure.
ここに来れば 絶対立ち直れるって
What was he thinking?
みつちゃん余計なことを
I think I'm getting over it now.
確かに俺立ち直れそう
That's not funny.
何なの!
He's a friend of yours, Nao?
何だ吉川の友達か? あっ彼氏とか?
I hope to be. But she's turned me down.
(阿部)彼氏候補です! いやフラれたけど フれた
Abe, don't talk about that.
(菜緒)ちょっとあべっち べつ
Wow. You're unexpectedly popular.
(一星)へえ ヘスー お前意外とモテんだな 丁んにな
What do you mean, "unexpectedly"?
意外は余計です
-Here you go. -Thank you.
(菜緒)はい (阿部)ありがとう
-Nao. -Yes?
吉川 (菜緒)ん?
Before the end of the year,
俺今年の恋は 今年のうちに忘れて
And I'll start looking for new love in the new year.
年明けから新しい恋を探すよ (菜緒) うん
I think you need to be a little more careful next year.
来年はもうちょっと 慎重になったほうがいいと思うよ
You know that's why they call you the king of the love confession.
だから告白大王なんて 呼ばれちゃうんだよ
But when I really like someone,
でも俺好きになった人には 好きって言わないと
Yeah, that's right. I know how you feel.
(一星)いやいいね! 俺は分かるよその気持ち
Issei, what are you talking about?
(菜緒)ちょっといっちゃん
I'm the type that says what I feel when I like someone.
俺も好きになったら 告白する派だな こな
Yep.
うん ちゃんと行動して後悔するより
Can I call you "teacher"? Ramen, please, teacher!
(阿部)師匠と呼んでいいですか? ラーメンください師匠!
-One order of ramen. -Coming right up.
(一星)ラーメン一丁! フーメン (徹平)あいよ 一徹
-You can go when you're done there. -OK.
(明)それ終わったら 上がっていいよ
-Hi, Uehara. -Oh, hi.
ひさし (ななこ)久志君 仩原)おう
Hey, Uehara,
(ななこ)ねえ久志君
when are you going to tell me your new address?
いつになったら 新しい家招待してくれんの?
I'll tell you when you catch up to my age.
俺の年に追いついたら 教えてやるよ
That's mean. I'll never catch up.
(ななこ)意地悪 追いつけるわけないじゃん
Nanako. You've got studying to do.
(明)ななこ お前勉強しなくていいのか?
I'm not studying until I get Uehara's address.
久志君の住所聞くまで 戻らない!
-Aw, jeez. Go ahead, you can leave. -Yes, sir.
(明)ったくもう…上がっていいよ つに (上原)はい
-Later. -Hey, Uehara.
じゃあな (ななこ)ねえ!久志君
After work on New Year's Eve,
大みそかのバイトの後
spend the New Year's countdown with us.
うちで一緒に年越しの カウントダウンしようね!
-Good bye. -Thanks. Bye.
お先でーす (明)はいお疲れさま
-Dad. -What is it?
(ななこ)お父さん (明)な…何だよ
-I know you have it. -What?
知ってるんだよねえ?
Uehara's new address.
久志君の新しい住所
That's personal information, you know.
それは個人情報だからね それは
Who could that be?
誰だろ
Yes?
(菜緒)はーいどうぞ
-Sorry for dropping in like this. -It's OK.
(百合)ごめんね急に (菜緒) ううん んん ごう
Where's Uehara?
久志は?
-I think he's working at the gas station. -Excellent.
スタンドでバイトだと思う 佰刽ラッキー
When he's around, he always pesters me to leave.
あいついるとすぐ帰れって うるさいからさ
-I bought us some donuts. -Really? Great!
ドーナツ買ってきたんだ~ (菜緒)え?やった!
Huh? You're still in your uniform? Isn't it winter vacation now?
あれ?菜緒ちゃん制服? 冬休みじゃないの?
School hasn't gone well... So I...
いろいろあってさ. 学校に
Remedial lessons, huh?
補習か
I had to take them too.
私もそうだったなあ
-What? You? -Uh-huh.
えつゆりりんも? 佰合) うん
Takuya, my husband,
卓也…って私の旦那様ね
he always got good grades, but mine were horrible.
卓也はいつも成績いいけど 私は全然ダメでさ
So his brains are inherited.
頭がいいのは血筋だったんだ
-Here you go. -Huh? New Year's gift money?
佰合)はいこれ (菜緒)ん?お年玉? し? はん )ノ
We'll be traveling, so can you give it to him on New Year's Day?
私たち年末から旅行だから 元日に菜緒ちゃんから渡して
Sure.
(菜緒) うん
The other day, I visited him at his job,
この間バイト先に 押しかけたけど
but he never actually listens.
あいつ話もまともに 聞かなくてさ
Oh, one of them is for you.
あつ1つは菜緒ちゃんに
What? No, I can't accept--
えついや そんな受け取れ…
No, no. This is a token of our appreciation.
いいの これは私と卓也の気持ちだから
Thanks for all you do for Uehara.
いつもありがとね 久志のこと
No, I don't do anything at all.
いや私は何も
And...
佰刽それと.
Ta-da! Kagami mochi.
ジャーン!鏡餅
It's gigantic.
デカい
What do you think about putting it here?
佰合) ここに飾ろっか どう?)ここに飾ろっか
Wow! It's amazing! I didn't know they sold ones this big.
あーすごい! こんな大きいの売ってるんだ
Cool, huh?
佰刽でしょ
Huh?
(菜緒)ん?
Yes?
はーい
-Who are you? -Uh... May I have your name?
あんた誰? (菜緒)え…どちら様ですが?
-Where's Uehara? -He's at work now.
久志君は? (菜緒)上 君はバイトで 原
-May I please have your name-- -What have you got to do with Uehara?
あのどちら様で (ななこ)あんたこそ久志君の何?
We live together.
同居人ですけど
What? Hey, out of my way!
はあ!?ちょっ…どいて
Wait a second! Hold it right there!
(菜緒)ちょっとちょっと ちょっと待ってよ!
-Oh, is that you, Nanako? -Oh, Yuri.
(百合)あれ?ななこちゃん? (ななこ)あっお姉さん!
What? You know each other?
(菜緒)えっお知り合い?
Who the heck are you?
あんた誰?
Who am I? I live with Uehara. My name's Nao Yoshikawa.
誰って…上原君の同居人の 吉川菜緒です
You told me that before.
それはさっき聞いた
But why are you living together?
だから何で 一緒に住んでんの?
Well, it's the result of several things...
それはいろいろありまして
Oh, but we're not sleeping together. We're merely living together.
あつでも同棲じゃなくて あくまでも同居ってこと.
Damn straight!
(ななこ)当ったり前でしょ!
There's no way in hell
あんたみたいな色気のない女
Uehara would fall for a girl with such little sex appeal as you.
久志君が好きになるわけ ないじゃん
How do you even know that?
何でそんな 言い切れるんですか!
Quit staring at me.
見ないで
Hey! What the hell are you doing?
あつあつ!ちょっ ちょっと何すんの!?
I can't even tell your front from your back.
そんな前か後ろかも 分かんないような体じゃ
I know Uehara would never try anything with you.
久志君も何もする気 起こらないよねえ
-Why you-- -Let me ask you this.
ちょっと! (ななこ) じゃあ聞くけど
Has he ever tried anything with you while living together?
久志君と一緒に住んでて 何かされた?
He hasn't, has he?
(ななこ) 何にもされてないでしょ?
No...
いや…
Obviously, he's not attracted to you at all.
(ななこ)女だと思われてないに 決まってる こ
Uehara has already promised
私は久志君と一緒に
to spend the New Year countdown with me.
年越しのカウントダウンする 約束もしたんだから
-Really? -Hey, you.
え? (百合)ちょっと 佰刽ちょっと
I thought I'd hear this out, but you're just making stuff up.
黙って聞いてりや 好き勝手言ってくれるじゃない
He only treats you nicely because you're his manager's daughter.
バイト先の店長の娘だからって 優しくしてりやいい気になって
What makes you think you're so sexy?
あなたにどれほどの色気が あるっていうのよ
Well, you see... I'm a C cup.
(ななこ)私はね Cカップあるのよ!
And you, Yuri, may look like you've got a nice rack,
お姉さんこそ一見 胸ありそうに見えるけどそれ…
but those are pads in your bra!
パッドでしよ!
What?
えっそうなの?
To tell you the truth...
(百合)実はね
How little you know.
青いわね いい?デカい胸ってのはね
sag with age.
年取るとたれるのよ
What...
なっ... なつ...
I'm still only 15. I'll work hard to keep them firm!
私はまだ15歳だもん 頑張ってキープするもん!
-Fifteen?
15!?
You sure look old!
あんた老けてるわねー!
How rude! I'm just mature-looking.
失礼な 大人っぽいって言ってくれる?
You're the one who's an old woman.
あんたこそ年増じゃん!
Hey! I'm still only--
ちょっと! 私はまだにじゅう…
Shut up! What the hell is all this racket?
(上原) うるせー 何騒いでんだよ な
You'll disturb the neighbors..
近所迷惑だ 心 / ...
Welcome home.
おかえり
Hey! Wait! Stop! Don't you dare run away!
(菜緒)ちよっちよつ… ちよつと
Are you nuts? What're they doing here?
何で逃げんのよ (上原)お前ふざけんなよ
These two are teasing me.
この2人が ななこのこといじめるの
-What a liar! -She's a different person.
何言ってんの? (菜緒)キャラ変わった
You shouldn't get involved with uncivilized people like them.
こんな野蛮な人たちとは 縁切ったほうがいいよ
Dad said the second-floor room might become vacant next month.
うちの2階来月には 空きが出るかもって
-Huh? -What?
仩原)え? (菜緒)えっ!? I? ええ 上菜
-You OK? -Yeah... I'm OK...
仩原)は? (菜緒)いや
Uehara, are you going to move again?
(百合)久志あんた また勝手に引っ越すつもり? こ
She's just making stuff up.
勝手に言ってるだけだろ
Hey, Nanako. Get home before it gets dark.
ほらななこ 暗くなる前に帰れよ
OK.
(ななこ)はーい
Dad said the second-floor room
(ななこ)来月には 空きが出るかもって
might become vacant next month. He'll rent it to you super cheap.
パパ言ってたし 格安で久志君に貸すって
-Huh? -What?
仩原)え? (菜緒)えっ!? I? ええ 上菜
Is he really going to move out?
引っ越すのかな
He must be at work.
(菜緒)バイトか
Huh? Who could that be?
ん?誰だろ
Yes?
はーい
Oh, Daichi. What's up?
おお大ちゃん どうしたの?
Remedial classes end today, right?
補習今日までだろ?
I've got practice too, so I thought we could go together.
俺も部活あるしさ 一緒に行こうと思って 俺!
-OK. -I've got something to tell you too.
(菜緒) うん (大地)あと話したいこともあるし
Is it true you're not going home for New Year's?
(大地)お前正月 田舎帰らないって本当?
News sure travels fast.
(菜緒)情報早すぎ
My mom heard from your mom.
休地おふくろが 菜緒のおばさんから聞いたって こつ
Yeah, there's a lot of reasons for it.
(菜緒) うんいろいろあってね
I mean, I just moved, and the cost of traveling is crazy.
ほら引っ越したばっかで こはつ 交通費もバカになんないし
Plus, I've got work.
それにバイトもあるし
Why don't you come stay at my place on New Year's Eve?
年越し うちに泊まりに来ないか?
-Huh? -Mom's worried about you.
え? (大地)おふくろも心配してたし 小
If you come, then we'll have New Year's soba together.
よかったら年越しそば 一緒に食べよう
Let's do our New Year's shrine visit at Hachiman too.
あと初詣行こう 八幡様
-We went there together last year too. -Uh-huh.
去年も一緒に行ったよね八幡様 (大地) うん
It doesn't really feel like a new year unless we go there.
あそこ行かないと 新年って感じしないんだよな
Uh-huh.
(菜緒) うん
I guess I'll go.
行こっかな
Tell your mom I'll be there.
おばさんにも よろしく言っとして
Got it.
分かった
OK, remedial lessons are over.
(教師)はいじゃあ 補習は以上になります
-Yes! -All right!
(生徒たちのはしゃぐ声)
Go ahead and have lots of fun
はいお前ら はしゃぎすぎんのはいいけど
but don't forget to review over New Year's.
年末年始もちゃんと 予習やっとけよ
Ah! Finally, it's over.
(まりな)あーやっと終わった
Mitsuishi.
(康太郎)光石 補習の打ち上げ行かね?
Oh... I'll go. I've got a little time before work.
(菜緒)ああ...行く ! バイトまで少し時間あるし
That'll be refreshing. Don't you agree, Marina?
何かスカッとさせたいんだよね ねつまりな
-I'm not going. -Really?
私行かない (菜緒)え?
Come here, Nao... Come with me.
ちょっと菜緒…いいから
What? What? What is it?
(菜緒)何何何… どうしたの?
What is it? What's wrong?
何どうしたの?
I need to talk with you about something alone.
話したいことがある 2人で
Really?
ん?
Wow. I can hardly believe it.
いやー信じられないわ
Believe what?
(菜緒)え?
That you're living with that stud.
あんなイケメンと 暮らしてるなんて
But...
でも私
Uehara doesn't find me attractive.
上原君に女として 見られてないから
It's more like we just happen to live together.
それに たまたま一緒に住んでるだけで
And who knows how long even this will last?
同居だって こつ いつまで続くか分かんないし.
Nao?
菜緒?
Oh, sorry. Forget about my problems.
あつごめん 私の話じゃなくて
What is it you wanted to talk about?
何?話って
Oh, yeah.
うん
To tell you the truth, Mitsuishi...
実はみつちゃんにさ
Yes?
ん?
He told me he likes me.
告白された
Huh? Uh...
(まりな)ん?えっ よ えつ
Nao? Hey, Nao!
菜緒?えっ菜緒!
Really?
ええ~!
-Don't exaggerate so much. -You've got to be kidding!
まりな)もう大げさだよ (菜緒)ウッソ~ !
It surprised me too.
(まりな) 私もびっくりしたけどさ
-When did he do it? -Christmas Eve.
(菜緒)えついつ? まりな)クリスマスイブ
-Then he really does love you. -You think so too?
それ本当の告白じゃん! (まりな)やっぱそう思う? 田う?
-Yes, of course! -Oh, dear.
うんそうだよ! (まりな)ああーどうしよう
I've never thought of Mitsuishi in that way before.
私今までみつちゃんのこと そういう目で見たことなかったし
I mean, there's nothing wrong with him,
それにみつちゃん 悪くはないけどさ
but he's also not really handsome.
イケメンではないじゃん?
But, listen to me, Marina.
でもまりな!
You have no idea how much courage it took for him to tell you that.
みつちゃんすっごい勇気出して 告白したと思うよ
That means he really loves you, Marina.
本当に好きなんだよ まりなのことが
-I understand that, but... -But what?
それは分かってるけど (菜緒)けど?
Ah! I don't know what to tell him.
ああ-もう分かんない!
Anyway, I don't dislike Mitsuishi.
でもみつちゃんのことは 嫌いじゃないし
I think he's a nice guy.
いい人だとは思う
Think it over, for Mitsuishi's sake as well.
みつちゃんのためにも ちゃんと考えてあげてね
I will.
うん
Nao!
菜緒~ ! 采緒~ !
-I feel so much better now. -I'm so happy for you.
もうスッキリした (菜緒) よかった
Here you go, Nao.
(徹平)はい菜緒ちゃんこれ
-Huh? -New Year's bonus.
(菜緒)え? (徹平)お年玉
No, I can't accept that from you.
いやそんな 受け取れません
It's hardly anything.
大した額じゃないから
Besides, this is our last day this year.
今日で今年の営業も おしまいだからな
Oh, Issei. Here's one for you too.
おつー星 お前にもやる 星も
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます
That's how you accept it, obediently.
ほらこうやって 素直に受け取るもんだよ
-Thank you very much. -You're welcome.
ありがとうございます (徹平)はい
-OK, see you next year, Nao. -Uh-huh.
じゃあ吉川もまた来年な (菜緒) うん
You two have a happy New Year.
店長もいっちゃんも よいお年を
What was this for?
(菜緒)何だっけ?これ
What are you up to?
(上原)何やってんの?
Like you said, I'm doing my New Year's cleaning.
(菜緒)言われたとおり大掃除
Like they say, "Clean out this year's dirt before the end of the year."
今年の汚れは 今年のうちにってね
Cleaning? Looks more like you're making a mess.
(上原)掃除ってか 散らかしてない?
How rude! I'm getting rid of the clutter.
失礼な 断捨離よ断捨離
Getting rid of clutter?
断捨離?
You take out all of your things
ある物を全部出して
then separate what you need from what you don't.
必要な物と不必要な物を 見分けるの
You just moved in. Is that all necessary? I"m not sure if you're bright,
お前引っ越してきたばっかで そこまでする必要があるって
or if you're stupid. I'm off to work.
ある意味すごいな 俺バイト行くから
See you... Oh!
(菜緒)いってらっしゃい あつ!
-Tomorrow, I'm going to Daichi's place. -You are?
私明日大ちゃんち行くから 仩 原)えつ
My mom told Daichi's mom about me
私のお母さんが 大ちゃんのおばさんと話して
so now I'm going to stay there for New Year's Eve.
大みそかは大ちゃんちに 泊まるってことになったの
I see. You must be happy.
ふーん いいんじゃねえの
Besides, I'll be out working.
俺バイトでいないし
Uehara has already promised
(ななこ)久志君と一緒に
to spend the New Year's countdown with me.
年越しのカウントダウンする 約束もしたんだから!
Oh, that's right.
だよね
It's cold.
寒っ... つ
Guess he's already at work.
もうバイトか…
Thank you.
(上原)ありがとうございました
Dang, it's cold.
さみ~
Huh?
えっ!?
What?
え...消えた
Where's the fuse box?
ブレーカーどこ?
Oh, there it is.
(菜緒)あつあつた つめつた
All right.
よいしょ
I think it's this one.
これか
OK. Are they back on?
よいしよ ついたか?
Huh? How come they're not on?
あれ? 何でついてないの?
Manager, I'm here.
店長お疲れさまです
Oh, Uehara. Is everything OK?
(明)おお上原君 無事だったか?
-Huh? -The blackout.
仩原)え? (明)いや停電
Isn't that where you live?
上原君ちのほうだろ?
Oh, I've been out since this morning.
ああ俺朝から出てたんで
Oh, yeah. I was worried about you.
(明)そっか心配してたんだよ 停電の影響で
Well, I'm glad you made it. That's good.
いやあよかったよかった そっかそっか
It's so cold.
(菜緒)寒っ 巷つ
Oh! That's cold!
うわっ冷たっ!
Huh? Why is there water here?
え…何で濡れてんの?
What? Oh, no.
to 5...
Oops!
おっヤバい
It's soaking wet here.
ビチョビチョじゃん
It's all melted.
溶けてる
Hello, Daichi?
(菜緒)もしもし大ちゃん 私だけど
I heard the trains have stopped. You want me to come get you?
電車止まってんだつてな 迎えに行こつか?
No, it's OK. The power is out here,
ううん うちのほう停電してるし
so I think it's better if I don't leave home.
家から出ないほうが いいと思って
-The power's out? -Uh-huh.
休地停電? (菜緒) うん 電ん
But I'm sure it'll come back on again pretty soon.
でもしばらくすれば つくと思うんだけどな
All right. I see.
(大地)そっか分かった
Is he there? Uehara?
あいついるのか? 上原
No.
ううん
I don't think he's coming home today.
だぶん今日は 帰ってこないと思う
I see.
そっか
But I'm perfectly fine. I don't mind being home at all.
でも全然平気だよ うちにいたらどうってことないし
OK, I see. Bye.
そつ そうか分かった じゃあな
Oh, Daichi. Have a happy New Year.
あっ大ちゃん よいお年を
Bye.
(菜緒) じゃあね
It sure is cold.
(菜緒)寒い。
Come to think of it,
そういやさ来月 ここの2階に空きがでるんだよ
So it's true.
その話本当だったんですね
-Oh, did Nanako say something? -Yeah.
(明)あっななこか 仩原)はい
But I didn't think it was true.
でも本当に 空くとは思ってなくて
Well, usually I rent it for $700.
まあ本来なら 7万で貸してるんだけど
-But for you, I'll rent it for $500. -Really?
上原君なら5万でいいよ 仩原)え?
But I can't pay for moving cost, though.
(明) まあ引っ越し代までは 出してやれないけどな
You're paying, what, $700 to $800 now, right?
今の所も 7~8万は払ってるんだろ?
Yes.
はい
In the long run, it's best to move to a cheaper place.
(明)長い目で見たら 家賃が安いに越したことはないぞ
And I'll provide meals here too.
ここなら まかないも食べられるし
But there is that pesky one here.
まあうるさいのはいるけどな
There has been a large scale blackout in parts of the Tokyo area.
(テレビ)東京都の一部の地域で 大規模な停電が起きています
The power company says that the power lines have been damaged.
電力会社は送電線に 何らかの故障があるとしていますが
However, they don't know what caused it.
原因はまだ分かっていません
Without any idea when the power will be back on, there are 3,500--
復旧のメドは立たず今も およそ3500…
Have a happy New Year!
(メールの着信音)
Are you OK, Nao?
もう充電なくなっちやうよ
OK, I've got to turn it off in case I need it for an emergency.
よしいざという時のために 切っておこう
Sorry everyone.
ごめんみんな
It's so cold.
(菜緒)冷た
I didn't know it could get so cold with the power out.
電気入ってないこたつって こんな冷たいんだ
I wish Uehara would come home.
上原君帰ってこないかな
You may as well go home.
(明)今日はもう上がっていいよ
But there might still be customers.
いやでもまだ お客さん来るかもしれませんし
I'll still pay you for the hours you're scheduled for.
(明)時給はさいつもどおり ちゃんとつけておくから
Take it easy on New Year's Eve, at least.
大みそかぐらい ゆっくりしろ
I appreciate it. Thank you.
すいません ありがとうございます
We're closed tomorrow, New Year's Day. Don't come in by mistake.
(明)あっ明日元日 うち休みだから間違って来るなよ
OK.
はい
Manager, thank you for all you've done this year.
店長 今年もお世話になりました
You have a happy New Year.
よいお年を
I will.
はい
The number you have dialed cannot be reached
(アナウンス) おかけになった電話は
because it has been switched off or--
電源が入っていないため
I wish I could tell everyone, "Happy New Year."
(菜緒) "よいお年を,,ぐらい 言いたいな
Oh.
あつ
Uehara called me.
上原君電話くれたんだ
Oh, please. Go through.
あつお願い繋がって
-Hello? -Oh!
(上原) もしもし (菜緒)あつ!
Hello. Uehara?
もしもし上原君?
Where are you now?
お前今どこ?
I heard the power's out at home.
うちのほう 停電してるみたいだけど
Uh-huh. It's really terrible...
そうもう大変なん
Huh? Are you OK?
え?大丈夫か?
Yes, I'm fine. Don't worry about me.
うん…ううん大丈夫 気にしないで
Enjoy the New Year countdown.
カウントダウン楽しんでね
OK, bye.
じゃあな
Oh!
あつ
Uehara.
(菜緒)上原君 仩原)ん? 緒原
Have a happy New Year.
よいお年を
Ouch! Oh, oops.
仩原)イテッ あっすいません
Nao? You here?
吉川?いるのか?
Yeah, I knew she wouldn't be.
やっぱいるわけないか
I'm here.
(菜緒)いるよ
What are you doing here?
(上原)お前何でいるんだよ!
I couldn't help it.
(菜緒)だって
Weren't you staying over somewhere?
(上原)今日泊まりじゃ なかったのかよ
The trains aren't running.
(菜緒) だって電車止まってるし
And the blackout caused problems with the fridge.
停電で冷蔵庫とか いろいろあって
Then why didn't you tell me?
(上原)そうならそうと言えよ
I thought it was odd your phone cut out all of a sudden.
突然電話切れるから 変だと思ったら
But I thought you were spending the countdown at Nanako's.
(菜緒)だってななこちゃんちで こつ カウントダウン…
I didn't want to bother you at work.
バイト邪魔したくなくて
-What about you, Uehara? -What about me?
上原君こそ何で? (上原)何でって
From the start, I said...
俺は最初から。
I told you to lean on me, right?
頼れって言っただろ
I'm sorry.
ごめん
-It sure is cold. -Uh-huh.
寒いな (菜緒) うん
Oh, it's lit.
あっついた
I got this candle at my brother's wedding.
これ兄貴たちの結婚式で もらったキャンドル
It's pretty.
きれい
I thought about throwing it away. Never expected it to be of use.
捨てようかと思ってたけど 意外なとこで役に立ったな
It's nice, warm and bright.
明るいしあったかいし
OK, I'm going to sleep here tonight.
よし!私今日 ここで寝よっと
Wait, Uehara.
ちょっ…上原君?
Huh? What happened?
えっ ? 何
Did I do something stupid again?
私また何かやっちゃつた?
But what?
え
If we're both in the same room, that'll make it warmer.
2人で同じとこいたほうが 部屋の温度上がるし
He's so close.
近い
You changed?
(菜緒)着替えたんだ
Of course. I'm going to bed, after all.
(上原)当たり前だろ 寝るんだから たら
Oh, yeah. You're right.
(菜緒)だよね
Man, it's cold.
(上 )あーさみ 原
-Don't you worry. -What?
仩原)安心しろ (菜緒)え?
I won't try anything with you.
(上原)襲ったりしないから
I know that.
(菜緒)分かってるよ!
Of all people,
上原君が私のこと 女として見てないのは
Don't you worry either.
安心して
At the very least, I don't even expect you to do anything like that.
私もそんなこと 1ミリも期待してませんから
I know that.
知ってるよ
Are you asleep, Uehara?
(菜緒)上原君寝た?
Yep.
寝た
Uhm...
あのさ
Did you leave home
上原君が家出たのって
because Yuri and your brother got married?
百合さんとお兄さんが結婚したから?
Why are you asking that now?
何だよ急に
I mean, you work so many jobs
(菜緒) だっていっぱいバイトして こつ
and suffer things you don't have to, so you could leave home...
しなくてもいい苦労ばっかして 家出て
I just thought it must have taken a lot of resolve to do that.
すごい覚悟がないと できないなって思って
Oh, I'm sorry. That's none of my business, is it?
あっごめん 余計なお世話だよね
Let me ask you this.
(上原)例えばさ
If you loved someone who didn't love you for eight years,
お前が8年間 片思いしてた相手がいたとしてさ
then that person got married to someone else,
そいつが他の奴と結婚して
could you be around them and still act normal?
その横で 平気な顔していられるか?
That's why I did it.
そんだけ
Won't you ever see your brother again?
(菜緒)お兄さんとは もう会わないの?
Yes, I will. It's not like I hate him.
仩原)いや 別に恨んじゃいないから
You see...
これは
the problem is my own.
俺の気持ちの問題だから
However... I never plan on returning home.
ただ俺は もう家に戻る気はない
Good night.
おやすみ
Oh!
(菜緒)あっ (上原)何だよ つだ
-Is it past midnight? -Way past.
(菜緒)もう12時過ぎた? (上原) とつくだろ
Happy New Year, Uehara.
あけましておめでとうごさいます 上原君
Best wishes in the new year.
今年もよろしくね
I'll try not to be too hard on you either.
お手柔らかに
I'm going to sleep now.
もう寝るぞ
OK, me too.
うん寝る
Ah, they came on. I'm so glad.
(菜緒)あーついた! よかった
-I wonder if the trains are running. -Why? Are you going somewhere?
電車動いてるかな (上原)何?どっか行くの?
Uh-huh. Daichi invited me to go to a New Year's shrine visit together.
(菜緒) うん 大ちゃんが 初詣一緒に行こうって
Oh, you want to come too?
あっ上原君も行く?
It's the New Year, and I think it's best to do that kind of thing.
新年だしそういうの ちゃんとしといたほうが
-What? You'll come? -You don't want me to?
えっ行くの? (上原)ダメなの?
Not at all.
全然
No, not at all. Let's go!
うん全然行こう!
Darn it, Uehara.
(菜緒)もう上原君が
Your dithering has made us late.
グズグズしてるから 遅くなっちゃったじゃん よつ
-You've got no right to say that. -Why?
(上原)人のこと言えないだろ (菜緒)は?
-You only told me this morning. -But you said you wanted to come.
(上原)今朝言うなよ (菜緒)そっちが来るって言ったから...
You should have told me yesterday.
(上原)昨日言ってくれれば よかったじゃん
Oh, give me a break.
(菜緒) うつさいな 大ちゃん!
Happy New Year.
あけましておめでとう
Best wishes in the new year.
今年もよろしくお願いします
I brought Uehara along.
上原君も連れてきたの
-Hi.
どうも 休地どうも
Was everything OK with the blackout?
大丈夫だったか?停電
Uh-huh, after Uehara came back home.
(菜緒) うん 上原君帰ってきてくれたから
Thanks.
ありがとな
No big deal. I just came to my own place.
いや別に 自分の家に帰っただけですから
That's right. You're acting like my parent, Daichi.
(菜緒)そうだよ 大ちゃん何か親みたい
I should have gone over myself.
俺が行ってやれたら よかったんだけどな
No, it's all right. Sorry for causing you to worry.
(菜緒) ううん ご心配おかけしました
That was a long prayer.
長いお願いだな
I probably overdid it for one dollar.
100円でちょっと 欲張りすぎたかな
Nao.
菜緒
I wanted to talk to you about something the other day.
この間 話そうと思ったんだけどさ
Yes?
(菜緒) うん
Uh, I'll tell you later.
あ...また今度話す
OK.
うん
I want a good luck charm.
(菜緒)私もお守り欲しい
You should get one for safety when traveling.
仩原) 交通安全でも買っとけお前
Good idea.
(菜緒) うん
Oh, it's Mitsuishi.
(菜緒)あつみつちゃん
Oh my god!
あっ!
Uh, I wish you all the best in the new year, Nao.
(まりな)あ 今年もよろしくね菜緒
Marina, did you...
(菜緒)もしかしてまりな
We're... going together now.
俺たち 付き合うことになりました
Congratulations.
おめでとう!
Thank you. This is thanks to you, Nao.
(まりな) ありがと菜緒のおかげだよ
Is that right?
そうなの?
What? Why are you crying?
(まりな)えっ!?ちょっと 何で菜緒が泣いてんの?
-Seriously? -I'm just so happy.
(光石)マジで? (菜緒) うれしくて
-Oh gosh, here. -Thank you.
(大地) しょうがねえなあ (菜緒)ありがとう
-Oh, you. Thank you so much. -Congratulations.
まりな)あーもうありがとう (菜緒)おめでとう
Mitsuishi getting that Great Fortune was so perfect.
みつちゃんの大吉 ヤバかったな
Who's Mitsuishi?
みつちゃんって誰?
-What? You don't know? -No.
(菜緒)えっウソ? 仩原)え?
He's been around since school started.
ずっといたじゃん 学校始まった時から
-Huh? -Crap.
(菜緒)ん? (上原)ゲッ
Crap.
ゲツ
Make yourselves at home.
ごゆっくり
You're so mean, Uehara.
(ななこ)久志君ひどい 仩原)あ?
We're supposed to do the New Years count down together.
カウントダウンしようって 言ったのに
You decided on that by yourself.
お前が勝手に 言ってただけだろ
I can't stand this.
もうイヤ 何で?
I've known you so much longer than her.
ななこのほうがずっと前から 久志君のこと知ってるのに
And I love you so much more than her.
ななこのほうが ずっと久志君のこと好きなのに
Move over to our place, Uehara.
久志君引っ越してきて
The second-floor room is only $500.
うちのマンションの2階 5万円だよ
It'll be cheaper than this place and easier to work there, right?
家賃今より下がるし バイトだってしやすくなるでしょ こつ
Your dad already told me that.
そのことなら 店長からも言われたよ
Then--
じゃあ…
I turned him down.
ちゃんと断ったよ つに
Why?
(ななこ)何で?
I'm still in high school and renting a new place isn't easy.
(上原)俺高校生だし 物件借り直すって大変なんだ
I'm sure Dad will do something to make it easier--
(ななこ)そんなのお父さんが 何とかしてくれるよ
Besides...
それに俺
I enjoy living here.
ここの暮らしが気に入ってるから 引っ越す気ないし
All right, now that you know how I feel, get home and study for entrance exams.
(上原)ほ~ら分かったら帰って 受験勉強頑張れ
Nao.
吉川
-I'm going to make dinner. You want some? -Uhm...
夕飯作るけど食べる? 仩原)あのさ
I know you haven't realized this, so I'm going to tell you.
お前気づいてないみたいだから 言うけど